Biographical files (UCLA University Archives Reference Collection). 1882- UARC.0745
UCLA Library Special Collections
UCLA University Archives. Biographical files (Reference Collection).
1882-
UCLA Library Special Collections
UCLA University Archives
UARC.0745
40 Linear Feet
Record Series 745 contains biographical information and photographs of faculty and staff affiliated with: the Los Angeles State Normal School (LASNS), 1881-1919; the University of California, Southern Branch, 1919-1926; the University of California, Los Angeles, 1927-. Materials include curriculum vitae, photographs, press releases, and newspaper clippings.
Conditions Governing Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance through our electronic paging system using the "Request items" button.
Acquisition Information
Sources for the Biographical Files (Reference Collection) include: UCLA Emeriti Center, UCLA faculty files, and the administrative files of UCLA offices and departments.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9973991483606533
Historical Note
The UCLA University Archives reference collection of biographical files was created ca.1986 and contain information on: faculty and staff of the Los Angeles State Normal School (LASNS), 1881-1919; faculty and staff of the University of California, Southern Branch, 1919-1926; faculty and staff of the University of California, Los Angeles, 1927-.
UCLA Golden Year Committee biographical files (former Record Series 285) are now part of Record Series 745. The Golden Year Committee was formed to commemorate the 50th anniversary of UCLA at the Westwood campus, 1929-1979.
Scope and Content
Record Series 745 contains biographical information and photographs of faculty and staff affiliated with: the Los Angeles State Normal School (LASNS), 1881-1919; the University of California, Southern Branch, 1919-1926; the University of California, Los Angeles, 1927-. Materials include curriculum vitae, photographs, press releases, and newspaper clippings.
UCLA Golden Year Committee biographical files (former Record Series 285) are now part of Record Series 745. The Golden Year Committee was formed to commemorate the 50th anniversary of UCLA at the Westwood campus, 1929-1979.
This is an active Record Series; additional University records are expected to be added.
The collection is organized into the following series:
Missing Title
Series 1. Biographical Files, 1882-
Series 2. Biographical Files - Photographs, 1882-
Series 3. Oversize Biographical Files, 1882-
- Biographical Files., 1882-; Series 1.
  - Aaron, Benjamin., b.1915 September 2 - d.2007 August 25
    General note
    UCLA faculty, Law.
  - Aarons, Miriam F., b. 1920 - d.2004
  - Abdou, Mohamed A.
    Distinguished Professor, Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Department (Henry Samueli School of Engineering and Applied Science).
  - Abdul-Jabbar, Kareem [Ferdinand Lewis Alcindor] (UCLA 1969).
  - Abe, Hitoshi.
  - Abidi, Asad.
  - Aboelata, Manal.
  - Ackerman, Page., b.1912 June 30 - d.2006 February 28
    UCLA reference librarian, 1949-1954; Assistant/Associate University Librarian for budget and personnel, 1954-1973; UCLA University Librarian, 1973-1977.
  - Ackerman, William Coit., b.1902 May 7
    William C. Ackerman (UCLA 1924) served on the faculty (physical education), as an athletic coach (tennis), and Executive Director of the Associated Students of UCLA (ASUCLA) from 1924-1967. Ackerman retired September 25, 1967.
  - Adams, Forrest H.
    UCLA faculty known for work in pediatric cardiology; director, UCLA Marion Davies Children's Clinic.
  - Adelson, David.
  - Adizes, Ichak., b. 1937.
  - Alexander, Charles J.
  - Allen, Raymond B., b.1902 - d. 1986
    Raymond B. Allen served as UCLA Chancellor, 1952 Nov. 15 - 1959 Sep. 1.
  - Allen, Rebecca.
  - Alleyne, Mark.
  - Alleyne, Reginald.
  - Allmindinger, Blake.
  - Altman, Ralph.
    Curator, Ethnic Collections (part of the Museum and Laboratory of Ethnic Arts.)
  - Amboss, Phyllis.
  - Andersen, Theodore A., b. 1920.
  - Anderson, Edward "Chip."
  - Anderson, John E., b. 1917 - d. 2011.
  - Anguiano, Lupe.
  - Anheier, Helmut.
  - Armenian, Haroutune.
  - Arnold, Jeanne E.
  - Arzouman, Susan.
  - Asanti, Molefi.
    Director, UCLA Afro-American Studies Center (appointed 1970); formerly known at Arthur L. Smith; name changed to Molefi Asanti c.1974.
  - Asarnow, Joan.
  - Ashe, Arthur (UCLA 1965)., b.1943 July 10 - d.1993 February 3
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes program for 1969 September 20-28 Pacific Southwest Open Tennis Championships (Los Angeles Tennis Club).
    Arthur Ashe became a professional tennis player.
  - Ashikaga, Ensho., b.1910 - d.1984
    UCLA faculty, Oriental Languages.
  - Assali, Nicholas., b.1916 - d.2004
  - Astin, Alexander.
    The Allan M. Cartter Professor of Higher Education(UCLA).
  - Astin, Helen S.
    UCLA faculty, Eduation; Associate Director of the Higher Education Research Institute (UCLA).
  - Atchison, Kathryn.
  - Atherton, Catherine.
  - Atkinson, James.
  - Bailey, Alison.
  - Bailey, Kenneth P. (UCLA Ph.D. 1938)
    Bailey received the first UCLA doctorate: Ph.D. in History, 1938; dissertation title: The Ohio Company of Virginia.
  - Bainbridge, Stephen.
  - Baldwin, Burr.
  - Ballerini, Luigi.
  - Baran, Annette.
  - Barker, Wiley F.
    UCLA clinical faculty, Surgery (School of Medicine).
  - Barnes, Ralph M., b. 1900 - d. 1984.
  - Baron, David.
  - Barrows, Robert Guy.
  - Barthol, Richard Paul., b.1919 - d.2004
  - Bartholomew, George A.
  - Bates, Marcia.
  - Beban, Gary.
    UCLA football quarterback, 1965(?)-1967 seasons.
  - Behdad, Ali.
  - Belt, Elmer., b.1893-d.1980
    General
    In the Fall 1961 Elmer Belt transferred his special collection of books and materials concerning Leonardo da Vinci and the Italian Renaissance to UCLA. The collection was later named the Elmer Belt Library of Vinciana.
  - Bemis, George W.
  - Bender, Gerald.
  - Bendiksen, Oddvar O.
    UCLA Faculty, Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Department(Henry Samueli School of Engineering and Applied Science).
  - Benefeld, Alan R.
  - Benfield, John R.
  - Bengelsdorf, Irving S.
  - Benn, James.
  - Benson, D.F. "Frank", 1928-1996
  - Berend, Ivan.
  - Bernardo, Antonio.
  - Berry, Ruth.
  - Birgeneau, Robert J.
  - Birkmeyer, Karl M.
    UCLA faculty, Art History; chairman of Art History Dept.
  - Birnbaum, Henrik.
    UCLA faculty, Slavic Languages and Literatures.
  - Blaustein, Joseph.
  - Block, Gene.
  - Bloom, Leonard. SEE: Broom, Leonard [NOTE: changed name from Bloom to Broom c.1949]
  - Blum, Richard C.
  - Boehm, John D.
  - Boelter, Llewellyn Michael Kraus., b.1898 - d.1966
    UCLA's first dean of Engineering. Arrived at UCLA in 1944, retired in 1965. Boelter conducted research on heat and mass transfer.
  - Boime, Albert Isaac., b.1933 March 17 - d.2008 October 18
    UCLA faculty, Art History.
  - Bollens, John C.
  - Bollens, Ross.
  - Bomba, Trudi.
  - Bonebakker, Seager Adrianus.
  - Boolootian, Richard A.
    UCLA faculty, Zoology.
  - Booth, Bradford A., b.1909 - d.1968
    UCLA faculty, English; husband of Josephine Conduitte Booth.
  - Booth, Josephine Conduitte. (UCLA 1933), b.1912 - d.1994
    UCLA faculty, English; wife of Bradford A. Booth.
  - Bouhoutsos, Jacqueline C., d.2008 May 22
  - Bourland, Roger.
  - Bowen, J. Donald.
    UCLA faculty, English.
  - Bowerman, Susan.
  - Bowyer, Ambrose., b.1883 - d.1950
  - Bowyer, Gladys Fryfogle., b.1888 - d.1968
  - Boyle, Barbara.
  - Boytner, Ran.
  - Bradbury, Ray.
    In 1950 and 1953 writer Ray Bradbury used the former UCLA Library typewriter rental room to compose his novel "Farenheit 451."
  - Bradbury, Thomas.
  - Bradley, Thomas (UCLA attended 1937-1940)
    Mayor of Los Angeles, 1973-1993.
  - Brant, Keith E. (UCLA 1983, M.A. 1988, Ph.D. 1995)
    Assistant Vice Chancellor for Alumni Relations and Executive Director of the UCLA Alumni Association ( - 2006 August 31); appointed UC-San Diego Vice Chancellor for External Relations as of 2006 September 1.
  - Brasel, Jo Anne.
  - Brennan, Michael J., b. 1942.
  - Brenner, Robert, b.1943
    UCLA faculty, History [U.S. economic historian).
  - Breslow, Lester., b.1915 March 17 - d.2012 April 9
    UCLA faculty, Health Services (School of Public Health); Dean, School of Public Health (1972-1980).
  - Brice, William J.
    UCLA Professor, Art.
  - Bright, William Oliver.
  - Bright, William R., d.2003 jul
    Bright founded Campus Crusade for Christ at UCLA in 1951.
  - Brook, Robert H.
  - Broom, Leonard., b.1911 November 8
    UCLA faculty, Sociology, 1941-1959. NOTE: name changed from Bloom to Broom c.1949.
  - Broome, Marian G., b.1934 June 24 - d.2009 December 22
  - Brown, Robert J.
  - Brown, William F., b. 1911.
  - Bruno, James.
  - Buffa, Elwood S., b. 1923 - d. 2005.
  - Bullock, Amy.
  - Bunche, Ralph Johnson. (UCLA 1927), b.1904 - d.1971
  - Burnett, Carol. (attended UCLA 1951-1954), b.1933 April 26
    Actress, comedienne, singer.
  - Burns, David.
  - Burns, E. Bradford., b.1932 August 28 - d.1995 December 19
    UCLA faculty, History.
  - Burns, Robert I., S.J., b.1921 August 16 - d.2008 November 22
  - Burr, Robert.
  - Burrell, Kenny
    Director, UCLA Jazz Studies Program.
  - Calderón, Héctor.
  - Caldwell, John.
  - Caldwell, Nikki.
  - Cameron, Sidney Herbert., b.1897 -
    Dean UCLA College of Agriculture and Assitant Director, Agriculture Experiment Station (appointed 1961 Jan.); UCLA faculty, Horticultural Sciences.
  - Campbell, Cameron.
  - Campbell, Liliy Bess., b.1883 - d.1967
    UCLA faculty, English, 1922-1950; UCLA Faculty Research Lecturer in 1935; authority on Elizabethan stage techniques and dramatic literature, especially the plays of Shakespeare.
  - Carlisle, Brian.
  - Carman, Gregory P., b. 1959-
  - Carpenter, Posie.
  - Carrabino, Joseph., b. 1923 - d. 2007.
  - Carron, Jean-Claude.
  - Cartter, Allan M., b.1922 June 17-d.1976 August
    UCLA faculty, Higher Education; Director of the Laboratory for Research on Higher Education (UCLA).
  - Caruso, Robert J.
  - Case, Fred E., b. 1918 - d. 2000.
  - Castaneda, Carlos Arana (UCLA 1962, Ph.D. 1973)., d.1998 April 27
    Includes 1973 UCLA dissertation in Anthropology.
  - Cates, Gilbert., b.1943 - d.2011
  - Catton, Ivan.
  - Chassiakos, Linda Reid.
  - Chen, Peter Pin-Shan., b. 1947.
  - Cheng, Lucie.
  - Chicago, Judith Sylvia Cohen. (UCLA 1962, Masters 1964)
    Judith Sylvia Cohen, later named Judy Chicago, artist.
  - Choi, Eunshil.
  - Chuang, Kenneth.
  - Ciavolella, Massimo
  - Cipriani, Hugo P. (UCLA attended 1938-1941)
  - Clark, Burton Robert., d.2009
    UCLA Allan M. Cartter Professor of Higher Education and Sociology.
  - Clark, Frank W.
  - Clark, James V.
  - Clark, Wesley K.
  - Clarke, Steven.
  - Clayton, Mayme.
  - Cline, Alex.
  - Cochran, Johnnie L., Jr.
  - Cohen, Yoram.
  - Condren, Edward I.
  - Consales, Judy.
    Director of the Louise Darling Biomedical Library (appointed c.2004).
  - Cook, Ian A.
  - Coombs, Robert Hofman.
  - Copeland, Thomas E., b. 1946.
  - Copenhaver, Brian.
  - Corbett, Charles.
  - Cornell, Bradford., b. 1947.
  - Cortinez, Veronica.
  - Coscarelli, Anne.
  - Cosentino, Donald.
  - Cotter, Anita.
  - Cox, Rebecca S.
  - Crabs, Donald B.
    UCLA faculty, Theater Arts; department chair, 1980-1984.
  - Crabtree, Charlotte A. (UCLA 1948)., b.1927 August 14 - d.2006 April 15
    UCLA faculty, Education (1961-1993); founding director of the National Center for History in the Schools (NCHS).
  - Craine, Theodore M.
  - Crandall, Paul H.
    UCLA faculty, Neurosurgery (UCLA School of Medicine). In 1963 Crandall was the first to carry out long-term depth electrode recordings of spontaneous seizuers in association with EEG telemetry monitoring.
  - Crandell [Crandall], Alice "Ma" Weller.
  - Crane, Randall D.
  - Crummett, Duane O.
    UCLA Lecturer and Assistant Professor, Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture (Department of Agriculture), 1949/50 to 1952/53.
  - Crump, Nadine.
    Served as the first administrator of the Los Angeles Office of the University of California Extension Division, 1917 August.
  - Culbert, Samuel A., b. 1938.
  - Cummings, Theodore E.
  - Dabagh, Thomas Suren., b.1903 February 12
    Associate Professor of Law and Law Librarian, 1949-1950; Director of the UCLA Law Library, 1950-1951 June.
  - Dagenais, John.
  - Dasgupta, Asim.
  - Dattoma, Lucia L.
  - Davis, Frank Cornelius., b.1896 - d.1983 April
    UCLA faculty, Psychology, 1931-1945; resigned from UCLA in 1945 due to "political activism" related to American Youth for Democracy.
  - Davis, Hiram Logan.
    Head, College Library, 1976-1979.
  - Davis, Louis E., b. 1918 - d. 1998.
  - Dawson, Muir, d.2005
  - Day, Robert.
  - De Robertis, Edward.
  - Dean, James Byron., b.1931 February 8 - d.1955 September 30
    Actor; attended UCLA Fall 1950.
  - Dean, Michael.
  - Debanney, Joseph G.
  - Delano, Annita., b.1894 October - d.1979 May 24
    UCLA faculty, Art.
  - De La Torre, Jose., b. 1943.
  - Dent, Robert William.
  - Devaskar, Sherin.
  - Dhir, Vijay K., b.1943 April 14
    UCLA Faculty and Chair, Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Department (Henry Samueli School of Engineering and Applied Science).
  - Diamant, Allison L.
  - Diamond, Jared Mason., b.1937 September 10
    UCLA faculty in Physiology (School of Medicine); MacArthur Fellow (1985); UCLA Faculty Research Lecturer (1996); 1998 Pulitzer Prize for "Guns, Germs, and Steel: the Fates of Human Society."
  - Dick, Hugh G., d.1972
    Includes announcements of the Hugh G. Dick Memorial Lecture in the Humanities.
    UCLA faculty, English (1937-1965?); UCLA faculty, Library Science (1967-1972?)
  - Diebenkorn, Richard Clifford. (b. 1922-d.1993) (Folder 1)
  - Dienstag, Joshua Foa.
  - Dignam, William Joseph.
  - Dixon, Wilfrid Joseph., b.1915-
  - Dolovich, Sharon.
  - Domingo, Placido.
    Placido Domingo appointed adjunct faculty, Music (February 1994).
  - Donahue, Katherine E. S.
    Head of History & Special Collections for the Sciences, UCLA Biomedical Library (retired 2008 July).
  - Donahue, Terry.
  - Dorcus, Roy M., d.1965
    UCLA faculty, Psychology; Professor of Psychology in the UCLA School of Medicine.
  - Dow, Arthur Wesley., b.1857 - d.1922 December 13
    See also: Arthur Wesley Dow Association. (UCLA University Archives Subject Reference Files)
  - Downey, Susan.
  - Dudley, George A., d.2005
  - Dukakis, Michael S.
    Includes: transcript (Commission on Presidential Debates) of 1988 October 13 U.S. Presidential debate between Republican Nominee, George Herbert Walker Buch, and Democratic Nominee, Michael S. Dukakis held at UCLA's Pauley Pavilion.
  - Dungey, Channing.
  - Duranti, Alessandro.
    Dean of Division of Social Sciences (appointed 2009 May).
  - Durrell, Cordell., b.1908 - d.1986
    UCLA Professor of Geology.
  - Dutton, Doug.
  - Dyball, Mark.
  - Dykstra, Clarence Addison., b.1883 - d.1950
    UCLA Provost, 1945-1950.
  - Edwall, Harry Robert.
  - Edwards, Sebastian.
  - Eiduson, Samuel.
  - Einstein, Albert.
    Albert Einstein visited UCLA to give an address in Royce Hall in 1932 February 15. Einstein's visit was sponsored by Sigma Xi (honorary science society).
  - Eiteman, David K., b. 1930.
  - Eisenberg, David.
  - El-Haddad, Mostafa.
  - El-Sayed, Mostafa A., b.1933 May 8
    UCLA Faculty - Physical Chemistry.
  - Emerson, Margaret.
  - Emerson, Robert M.
    UCLA Faculty, Sociology Department. Includes: "Report on the 1981 Conference on Social Science Fieldwork in the University of California" (1981 July)
  - Enderton, Herbert Bruce., d.2010
    UCLA faculty, Mathematics.
  - Engelke, Marian Elizabeth., b.1921 - d.2009 December 25
    Library staff artist, 1964-1984.
  - Enstrom, James.
  - Erickson, Mary.
  - Erickson, Robert.
  - Erlenkotter, Donald., b. 1938.
  - Estrin, Gerald.
    UCLA faculty, Computer Science.
  - Ettinger, Jerome.
  - Evans, Leslie.
  - Fahey, John.
  - Faine, Hyman., b. 1910 - d. 1999.
  - Fairbanks, Lynn.
  - Farb, Sharon E.
  - Fargo, Elizabeth H.
    Assistant Librarian 1899 to c.1922.
  - Farquhar, David M.
    UCLA faculty, History Department.
    Biography/History
    Died 1985 August 9.
  - Farrell, John B., b.1922 - d.2008
  - Favretto, Christina.
    UCLA Library. Rare Books Curator, Department of Special Collections. (2005 Aug- )
  - Felixson, Carol.
  - Fenberg, Sylvia Gene Krupin (UCLA 1933).
    Includes Fenberg's "Bread Without Butter" (c.1962), recollections about her last year as a UCLA student and time spent (post-graduation) hitch-hiking across the United States during the Depression.
  - Ferguson, Christopher (UCLA 1986, Ph.D. 1999)
    Ferguson also known as professional poker player Chris 'Jesus' Ferguson.
  - Ferguson, Russell.
  - Ferguson, Sherman.
  - Fielder, Eve Picardy., b.1941 August 23 - d.2008
  - Fielding, Jonathan.
  - Fink, Robert M.
    UCLA faculty, Physiological Chemistry (School of Medicine)
  - Finn, Paul.
  - Fischer, Robert A. (UCLA 1945), d.2000 February 20
    Served as UCLA Director of Athletics (1980-1983).
  - Fishburn, Luke Warren.
  - Fong, Peggy.
  - Foot, Philippa., b.1920 October 3 - d.2010
    Foot was the UCLA Gloria and Paul Griffin Professor of Philosophy.
  - Fortier, Renée.
  - Fowler, Audree.
  - Frand, Jason L., b. 1942.
  - Frankovich, Mitchell J. (UCLA 1935)
  - French, Susan F.
  - Fried, Hzhak.
  - Friedlander, Jonathan.
  - Friedlander, Sheldon K., b.1927 - d.2007
    UCLA Parsons Professor of Chemical Engineering.
  - Frosh, Dominick L.
  - Gabor, Ivan.
  - Gabriel, Stuart A.
  - Gandara, Patricia.
  - Garfinkel, Harold., b.1917 October 29
    UCLA Professor, Sociology.
  - Garrell, Robin.
  - Garrels, Gary.
  - Garro, Linda.
  - Gatti, Richard.
  - Gehring, Kimberly.
  - Gehry, Frank.
  - Geller, Fred M.
  - Geoffrion, Arthur M., b. 1937.
    UCLA Faculty, James A. Collins Professor of Management; Decisions, Operations, and Technology Management (Anderson Graduate School of Management).
  - George, Robert.
  - Gere, David.
  - Gersick, Connie J. G., b. 1948.
  - Gershwin, George.
    Includes information related to George Gershwin's musical score, "Strike Up the Band."
  - Geschwind, Daniel.
  - Ghamlouch, Hassan.
  - Ghez, Andrea M.
    UCLA Professor Physics and Astronomy. 2003 UCLA Faculty Research Lecturer; 2008 MacArthur Prize Fellow.
  - Ghoniem, Nasr M.
  - Gibbs, Silas Paul.
    UC-Southern Branch basketball team 1922, 1923.
  - Gibson, Arthur C.
    Director, UCLA Botanical Garden.
  - Gibson, James Steven.
  - Gibson, Mel.
  - Gilhousen, Howard C., b.1895 - d.1969
    Professor UCLA Department of Psychology; department chair, 1955-1959.
  - Gilman, Nelson.
  - Gilman, Peter Thomas (UCLA 1951)., b.1927 - d.1999
    Author of "Diamond Head, a novel" (1960).
  - Gilmore, Sidney H.
  - Gipstein, Robert M.
  - Gladstone, Dick.
  - Glater, Julius.
  - Glick, Dudley Hillel., b.1920 jun 9 - d.2007 jun 27
    UCLA Dental School faculty, 1995-2007(?).
  - Go, Vay Liang W.
  - Gold, Marvin H. (UCLA 1937)
    UCLA undergraduate, B.S. in Chemistry (1937). Became highly regarded defense and aerospace industry researcher.
  - Golde, David William, b.1940 - d.2004
  - Gondek, Juliana.
  - Gong, Henry.
  - Gonzales, Manual Pedro.
    UCLA Professor of Spanish.
  - Gonzalez, Elma.
  - Goodman, John William.
  - Goodwin, John Edward., b.1876 oct 1 - d.1948 nov 18
    Served as UCLA Librarian, 1923-1946.
  - Gordon, H. Earl.
  - Gordon, Kate.
    UCLA faculty, Philosophy and Psychology (c.1922/1923-1923/1924); Philosophy (1924/1925-1930/1931).
  - Gorney, Roderic., b.1924
    UCLA Professor of Psychiatry.
  - Gouw, Julia.
  - Graham, Robert.
  - Granfield, Michael E., b. 1943.
  - Grant, Ulysses S. IV, b.1893 May 23 - d.1977 March
    Grandson of U.S. President Ulysses S. Grant; UCLA Professor of Geology, 1931-1959.
  - Graual, Hugh M., b.1918 - d.2009
  - Gray, Gary.
  - Gray, Hugh J., b.1900 Sep 4 - d.1981 Feb 13
    UCLA Professor of Theater Arts (Motion Picture and Television).
  - Greenberg, Alice Brooking.
  - Greenwald, Joanne.
  - Gregory, George. (UCLA 1942), d.2005 March
    Benefactor of the UCLA Chemistry and Biochemistry Department.
  - Grelia, Christine.
  - Gupta, Vijay., b. 1963-
  - Gura, Victor.
  - Gurval, Robert.
  - Haberfeld, Felicia.
  - Haft, J. David.
  - Hagge, Carl William.
  - Hahn, H. Thomas.
  - Haldeman, Harry Robert (UCLA 1948).
    Includes photocopy of 1970 May 7 letter to U.S. President Richard Nixon [c/o H. R. Haldeman, Assistant to the President of the United States] from the 1970 UCLA Mens Basketball team regarding the war in Southeast Asia (Vietnama and Cambodia) and the deaths of Kent State University students by the Ohio National Guard.
    Also known as H.R. "Bob" Haldeman. Served as Assistant to U.S. President Richard M. Nixon.
  - Halma, Holmes., d.2008
  - Halpern, Steven Joel (UCLA 1973).
    Includes Halpern's campaign literature for UCLA Undergraduate Students Association general representative (1970-1971), vice president (1971-1972), and president (1972-1973).
    Halpern served as UCLA undergraduate student body president, 1972-1973.
  - Hamilton, Albert Wilkin.
    UCLA student 1932 September to 1934 [January?]. Joined UCLA student William Alonzo Reynolds in declaring conscientious objector status regarding compulsory courses offered by the UCLA Military Science and Tactics Dept. (affiliated with the Reserve Officer Training Corps/ROTC); see: U.S. Supreme Court case Hamilton v. Regents of the University of California (1934).
  - Hammer, Armand., b.1898
    Armand Hammer-Occidental Petroleum Laboratories, within UCLA's Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Institute, established and named in September 1977 by UC Board of Regents. Hammer served as Chairman of the Board and Chief Executive Officer, Occidental Petroleum Corporation.
  - Hammond, Peter B., 1 folder
    UCLA Anthropology Professor and member of Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Studies (LGBS) Task Force in 1994-1995.
  - Handler, Harry., d.2005
  - Hanley, Edwin H.
  - Hansen, Mark.
  - Hanssens, Dominique.
  - Harary, Isaac M.
  - Haraszty, Eszter (Mrs. Bruce David Colen)., b.1920 - d.1994 Nov. 30
  - Hardwick, E. Russell.
    UCLA Professor of Chemistry.
  - Harper, Kenneth E.
  - Harris, Chandler. (UCLA 1936), d.2005 June 24
    Director, UCLA Public Information.
  - Harrison, Gilbert (UCLA 1937).
    Gilbert Harrison was editor of "The New Republic."
  - Hays, Esther Fincher.
    UCLA Professor, Nuclear Medicine and Radiation Biology.
  - Hearn, Guy Edward., 1913 Nov. 19 - 1987 April 22
    UCLA faculty, Theater Arts.
  - Heber, David.
  - Hedrick, Earle Raymond., b.1897 - d.1943
    UCLA Provost, 1937-1942.
  - Herrick, Samuel., b.1911 May 29 - d.1974 March 20
    UCLA faculty, Astronomy (1937-1974).
  - Hershberger, Mary Martin.
  - Hershey, Mira., d.1930
    Also known as Almira Parker Hershey.
  - Hildemann, William H.
    UCLA faculty, Infectious Diseases; UCLA faculty, Medical Microbiology and Immunology; Director, Dental Research Institute, UCLA School of Dentistry (1972 March).
  - Hirabayashi, Lane Ryo.
  - Hirsch, Werner Z., b.1920 June 10 - d.2009 July 10
    UCLA faculty, Economics (1963-1990) and founding director of UCLA Institute of Government and Public Affairs.
  - Hirshleifer, David A., b. 1958.
  - Hirshleifer, Jack.
  - Ho, Chih-Ming.
  - Hobbs, Douglas Stillman., b.1934 - d.2003
    UCLA faculty, Political Science.
  - Hoeber, Ralph C., b. 1898 - d. 1978.
  - Hoek, Eric.
  - Hollawder, Daniel.
  - Hood, Mantle.
    UCLA faculty, Music; affiliated with the UCLA Institute of Ethnomusicology.
  - Hoover, Lou Henry., b.1874 - d.1944
    Wife of U.S. President Herbert Hoover; attended Los Angeles State Normal School (LASNS) 1891-1892, Junior class.
  - Hoover, Thelner. (UCLA 1930)
  - Horn, Andrew Harlis., b.1914 - d.1983